Guide to the Frank Lyon Polk Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1898-(1915-1920)-1942; Series I; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Walker, Harold, 1917 April - May (Box 13, Folder 466)
    See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 458 See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 472 See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 484 See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 487
  - Walker, Henry Freeman, 1914 January (Box 13, Folder 466)
  - Walker, John Randall, 1918 November (Box 13, Folder 466)
  - Wallace, Hugh Campbell, 1920 March - Jun, 1921 January (Box 13, Folder 467)
  - Wallerstein, David, 1916 December - 1917 February (Box 13, Folder 467)
  - Walling, William English, 1917 May, August (Box 13, Folder 467)
  - War Prisoners' Aid
    See: A. C. Harte, box 7, folder 245
  - Warburg, Paul Moritz
    - 1919 August - October (Box 13, Folder 468)
      See also: American Mission, box 22, folder 103
      See also: Germany, box 26, folder 301
    - 1920 January (Box 13, Folder 469)
  - Wardwell, Allen, 1920 February - April (Box 13, Folder 470)
  - Warfield, Lewis
    See: Mexico, box 29, folder 491
  - Warren, Charles
    - 1915 October - November (Box 13, Folder 471)
      See also: Germany, box 25, folder 281
    - 1917 March - April (Box 13, Folder 472-473)
    - (*), 1917 May - 1918 Jan, 1920 Jun, 1924 July - August (Box 13, Folder 474)
  - Washburn, H. C., 1924 July (Box 13, Folder 475)
  - Washington Post, 1917 [Jul?] - August (Box 13, Folder 475)
  - Washington Zionist Circle
    See: E. W. Lewin-Epstein, box 9, folder 326
  - Wason, Edward H., 1915 December (Box 13, Folder 475)
  - Waterbury, Lawrence, 1920 January (Box 13, Folder 475)
  - Watriss, Frederic N.
    - (*), 1915 October - 1917 December (Box 13, Folder 476)
    - 1918 January - December (Box 13, Folder 477)
    - (*), 1919 January - June (Box 13, Folder 478)
    - 1919 December - 1920 May (Box 13, Folder 479-480)
  - Welch, David, 1917 August (Box 13, Folder 481)
  - Welles, Roger, 1918 June (Box 13, Folder 481)
  - Wells Fargo and Company Express, S. A.
    See: Mexico, box 29, folder 499
  - Westroff, Henry I., 1918 September (Box 13, Folder 481)
  - Whalen, Grover A., 1922 Nov, 1929 December (Box 13, Folder 482)
  - Wherry, William M., Jr., 1917 March (Box 13, Folder 482)
  - Whigham, Henry James, 1915 November (Box 13, Folder 482)
  - Whipple, Sherman Leland, 1918 October (Box 13, Folder 483)
  - White, Francis, 1925 April (Box 13, Folder 483)
  - White, Henry, 1919 Jul, 1925 November (Box 13, Folder 483)
    See also: Adriatic Question, box 21, folders 7-20 See also: Adriatic Question, box 21, folders 39-47 See also: Rumania, box 32, folder 653
  - White, John Beaver, 1919 October (Box 13, Folder 483)
  - Whitelock, Deming and Kemp, 1917 March (Box 13, Folder 483)
  - Whitlock, Brand, 1915 Dec; 1916 Aug, October; 1917 October (Box 13, Folder 484)
  - Wickersham, George W., 1917 May, November (Box 13, Folder 484)
  - Wilkie, John E., 1917 August (Box 13, Folder 484)
  - Willard, Belle Layton Wyatt (Mrs. Joseph Edward), 1925 May (Box 13, Folder 485)
  - Willard, Joseph Edward, 1917 March (Box 13, Folder 485)
  - Willert, Arthur, 1918 December (Box 13, Folder 485)
  - Williams, Edward T.
    See: Japan, box 28, folder 388 See: Japan, box 28, folder 392 See: Russia, box 33, folder 676 See: Siam, box 34, folder 746
  - Williams, R. H., 1915 September (Box 13, Folder 485)
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt (Mrs. Woodrow), [1919 Jul?]; 1920 May; 1924 [Feb?], Apr; 1928 Apr; 1931 Jun; undated (Box 13, Folder 486)
    See also: Woodrow Wilson (1919 Nov - 1920 Mar), box 14, folders 508-515
  - Wilson, Thomas Woodrow
    See: Woodrow Wilson, box 14, folders 488-516
  - Wilson, William Bauchop, 1919 June (Box 13, Folder 487)
  - Wilson, Woodrow
    - (*), 1915 August - 1917 April (Box 14, Folder 488-494)
    - 1917 June - July 11 (Box 14, Folder 495)
    - (*), 1917 July 12-18 (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - 1917 July 21-23 (Box 14, Folder 497)
      See also: William C. Redfield (1919 Jun 6; enclosing Polk to Wilson, 1917 Jul 12), box 12, folders 415-416
    - 1917 July 24-31 (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - (*), 1917 August - 1918 July 26 (Box 14, Folder 499-502)
    - 1918 July 27 - September (Box 14, Folder 503-505)
    - (*), 1918 October - 1919 July (Box 14, Folder 506-507)
    - 1919 November - 1924 January (Box 14, Folder 508-516)
  - Winslow, Lawrence Lanier, 1920 May - June (Box 14, Folder 517)
  - Wiseman, William
    See: Gordon Auchincloss (1918 Jun 28, Aug 17), box 1, folder 17
  - Woods, Arthur, 1909 Jun, 1916 Mar, [1918 May?], 1922 April (Box 14, Folder 517)
  - (*) Woolsey, Lester Hood, 1919 Nov; 1920 January, Jun; 1932 January - February; 1942 January - February (Box 14, Folder 518)
    See also: Austria, box 22, folder 133 See also: Canada, box 24, folder 183 See also: Germany, box 25, folder 282 See also: Germany, box 25, folder 292 See also: Ireland, box 27, folder 371 See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 487 See also: Mexico, box 29, folder 495 See also: Miscellaneous, box 30, folder 525 See also: Spain, box 34, folder 755 See also: Treaty of Versailles, box 35, folder 809
  - World Peace Association
    See: Post Office Department, box 32, folder 638
  - Wright, Joshua Butler, 1925 Dec, 1927 March (Box 14, Folder 518)
    See also: Nicaragua, box 31, folder 569 See also: Panama, box 31, folder 579
  - Wyvell, Manton M.
    See: Trade, box 35, folder 786
  - Yacouboff, L., 1919 August (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - Yale, William
    See: Near East, box 31, folders 549-550
  - Yale Club, 1921 February (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - Yale University, President and Fellows, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - Young, Owen D., 1922 November (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - Young, W. J.
    See: Hamilton Fyfe (1917 Aug 16), box 6, folder 195
  - Young Men's Christian Association
  - Zionist Organization of the United States
  - Unidentified, 1916-1920, 1942, undated (Box 14, Folder 520)
  - Letterbooks
    - 1915 February 3 - September 14 (Box 15, Folder 521)
    - 1915 September 18 - 1916 April 20 (Box 16, Folder 522)
    - 1915 December 9 - 1916 March 4 (Box 16, Folder 523)
    - 1916 August 5 - 1917 January 22 (Box 16, Folder 524)
- Diaries, 1915-1920; Series II; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The series is in this order: manuscript books, 1916-1917; typed pages arranged alphabetically by country, 1915-1917; typed pages arranged chronologically, 1917-1920; appointment book, 1919.
  - Manuscript books
    - 1916 Mar 29 - Oct 21 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1917 Jan 2 - Oct 27 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Typed pages by country
    - Argentina: 1915 Sep 27 - 1916 Apr 11 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Austria: 1915 Oct 21 - 1917 Mar 15 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Belgium: 1916 Jun 27 - 1917 Feb 10 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Bolivia: 1916 Jul 27 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Brazil: 1917 Feb 1 - Apr 16 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Britain: 1915 Sep 30 - 1916 Jul 27 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Britain: 1916 Aug 4 - 1917 Apr 13 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Bulgaria: 1916 Oct 4 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Chile: 1916 May 13 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - China: 1916 Jul 26 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Colombia: 1916 Jul 10 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Costa Rica: 1916 Jun 2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Cuba: 1917 Feb 8 - Apr 17 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Denmark: 1915 Dec 7 - 1917 Feb 15 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Ecuador: 1916 May 23 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - El Salvador: 1916 Oct 5 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - France: 1915 Nov 9 - 1917 Apr 13 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Germany: 1916 Feb 1 - 1917 Feb 12 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Greece: 1915 Nov 20 - 1917 Feb 16 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Guatemala: 1916 Mar 20 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Haiti: 1915 Oct 4 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Italy: 1916 Feb 1 - 1917 Feb 20 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Japan: 1915 Oct 18 - 1917 Apr 9 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Mexico: 1915 Oct 23 - 1917 Jan 31 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Netherlands: 1915 Oct 19 - 1917 Feb 3 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Nicaragua: 1916 Mar 16 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Norway: 1916 Feb 25 - Oct 17 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Panama: 1916 May 19-23 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Peru: 1916 Jun 2 - Oct 5 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Russia: 1916 Apr 19 - Oct 9 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Spain: 1916 Mar 16 - 1917 Feb 3 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Sweden: 1915 Nov 6 - 1917 Apr 17 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Switzerland: 1916 Mar 16 - 1917 Feb 16 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Uruguay: 1916 Nov 25 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Typed pages by date
    - 1917 April 23 - 1918 October 15 (Box 18, Folder 36-53)
    - 1918 October 16 - 1919 August (Box 19, Folder 54-72)
    - 1919 September 1 - 1920 May 22 (Box 20, Folder 73-80)
  - Appointments: 1919 (Box 20, Folder 81)
  - Non-circulating duplicates, 1915-1918 (Box 64)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Permission of the head of Manuscripts and Archives is necessary to examine these materials.
  - Non-circulating duplicates, 1918-1920 (Box 65)
- Subject Files, 1912-(1915-1921); Series III; 7 linear feet (7 boxes)
  The sections are in alphabetical order. The arrangement of each section is chronological.
  Many letters and memoranda in this series are not listed by writer. Some of the listed and some of the unlisted items can be located by writer from cross-references in the folder listing for Series I. The description of that series (p. 6) explains which items can be located in this way.
  - Adriatic Question
    - Allied Naval Committee for the Adriatic: minutes of meeting (copy, in translation), 1919 February 25 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - American Commission to Negotiate Peace, Chiefs of the Austro-Hungarian, Balkan, and Italian Divisions and the Intelligence Section of the Boundary Geography Division: memorandum to the Commissioners re: "Dalmatia and Fiume" (carbon), 1919 March 18 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "Memorandum of Rear Admiral A. P. Niblack, U.S. Navy, Regarding Fiume and Dalmatia,", 1919 April 5 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - [Woodrow Wilson]: "Memorandum as to a Suggested Basis for Settlement of the Adriatic Question Submitted for Elaboration and Definition by Experts" (annotated copy), [1919 June 15] (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Woodrow Wilson: memoranda and covering letters to Lansing (copies), 1919 June 25-28 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Brief Notes on a Meeting [of Clemenceau, Lansing, Balfour, and Tittoni] which took place in M. Clemenceau's Office in the Ministry of War at 2:30 P.M. July 3, 1919" re: Italian interests in Asia Minor, the Adriatic, and the Klagenfurt Basin (carbon), 1919 July 7 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Notes on Informal Conversation between Mr. Henry White and M. Tittoni on July 4, 1919" re: Italian interests in Asia Minor and the Adriatic (carbon), 1919 July 7 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Commissioners Plenipotentiary: draft cable to the Secretary of State re: conversation with Tittoni, [1919 July 8?] (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Interallied Commission of Inquiry (Fiume): daily reports (copies), 1919 July 28 - August 6 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Commission Interalliée d'Enquête de Fiume: Procès-verbaux et rapport, [1919 post-August 9] (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - [Frank L. Polk?]: memorandum to Admiral Knapp re: conversation with Mr. Pachitch about drafting of Italians in the Spalato district, 1919 August 14 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Frank L. Polk: draft cables to the Secretary of State, 1919 August 14-15 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - H. S. Knapp: letters to Polk enclosing copies of letters from Rear Admiral Andrews, 1919 August 19 - September 2 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Frank L. Polk: cables exchanged with the Secretary of State (copies, one edited), 1919 August 22-26 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - [Yugoslavian Delegation]: memorandum re: "What Italy Can Receive with the Consent of the Jugoslavs,", 1919 August 25 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Douglas W. Johnson: draft letter for Admiral Knapp to be sent to Admiral Andrews re: Andrews's letter of Aug 16, 1919 August 28 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Douglas W. Johnson: "Draft telegram to the President" (draft, copy for transmission), 1919 August 28-29 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - [Georges Clemenceau]: memorandum of Tittoni's proposed terms of settlement, [1919 August 30] (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Henry White and Douglas W. Johnson: draft cable re: conversations with Tittoni and recommended U.S. response to Italian claims, [1919 August 30] (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Frank L. Polk: cable to the Secretary of State (draft, copy), 1919 August 31 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Frank L. Polk: cables exchanged with the President and the Secretary of State (drafts, copies), 1919 September 2-4 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Henry White and Tasker H. Bliss: letter to Polk re: agreement with the British and French representatives on the Supreme Council, 1919 September 2-16 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - H. S. Knapp: memorandum re: border relations between Italian and Serbian troops, 1919 September 3 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Frank L. Polk: letter to Balfour re: the President's probable attitude toward the latest Italian proposal (carbon), 1919 September 5 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Georges Clemenceau and David Lloyd George: "Projet de cable au President Wilson" (carbon, copy in translation), 1919 September 5 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Frank L. Polk: cable to the Secretary of State transmitting proposed cable from Clemenceau and Lloyd George (draft, originating copy), 1919 September 6-10 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - [Giacomo de Martino]: proposed terms of settlement (copies, in French and in English translation), 1919 September 11 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - [Douglas W. Johnson]: "Proposed Draft Telegram to the President" (original, copy for transmission by Polk), 1919 September 11, 17 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Office of the Naval Adviser: memoranda re: telegrams from Rear Admiral Andrews in Fiume, 1919 September 14 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Woodrow Wilson: cable re: proposed terms of settlement (copy as received, annotated), 1919 September 14 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Memorandum re: "Proposed Settlement of Adriatic Question" acceptable to Wilson (carbon), 1919 September 16 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - N. A. McCully: letters to Polk enclosing copies of letter and other papers from Rear Admiral Andrews, 1919 September 14-24 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Draft memorandum re: "Proposed Settlement of Adriatic Question" acceptable to Wilson (carbon), 1919 September 15 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Memorandum re: positions of Tittoni, Lloyd George, and Clemenceau, [1919] September 15 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - [Italian Delegation?]: memorandum, "Question de l'Adriatique" (carbon, in French; mimeo, in English translation), [1919 September 15?] (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Allen W. Dulles: memorandum re: memorandum, "Proposed Settlement of Adriatic Question" (annotated; copy?), 1919 September 16 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Tommaso Tittoni: letter to Polk enclosing draft cable to the President, 1919 September 16 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Frank L. Polk: cable to the President and the Secretary of State re: the Adriatic question (draft, copy, attached memorandum), 1919 September 17 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Douglas W. Johnson: letter to Polk, [1919] September 17 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Georges Clemenceau: message to the President (original, edited copy in translation, covering cable by Polk), 1919 September 18 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Frank L. Polk: draft cable to the President and the Secretary of State, 1919 September 22 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Serbian Legation, Paris: report of conversation with an emissary of Gabriele D'Annunzio re: D'Annunzio's plans and preparations, 1919 September 25 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - N. A. McCully: Letters and memoranda to Polk enclosing copies of miscellaneous papers, 1919 September 25-30 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Frank L. Polk: cables exchanged with Peter A. Jay, American chargé d'affaires, Rome (draft, copies, attached concurrence by Henry White), 1919 September 25 - October 1 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Frank L. Polk: cables to the President and the Secretary of State (edited copies), 1919 September 25 - October 1 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - British Delegation: memorandum to Commander H. W. Koehler re: union of the Fourth Regiment of Bersaglieri with the rebels in Fiume, 1919 September 29 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Map showing "Distribution of Troops in and around Fiume,", [1919 Sep?] (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Map of the Port of Fiume, [1919 Sep?] (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - N. A. McCully: memoranda exchanged with Polk enclosing copies of miscellaneous papers, 1919 October 1-31 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - G. Howland Shaw: memorandum quoting cables from the Italian Foreign Office to the Italian Delegation re: Serbian charges of Italian military preparations, 1919 October 7 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - [Henry White]: memorandum of conversation with Scialoja and Martino re: proposed terms of settlement (carbon), 1919 October 8 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Leland Harrison: summary of events, Sep 10 - Oct 1, for Henry White, 1919 October 9 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Henry White: memorandum to Polk re: conversation with Martino, 1919 October 9 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Memorandum, "Proposed Settlement of Adriatic Question. (Revision of draft Sept. 16th)" (annotated), 1919 October 10, November 29 (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - Draft revision of Lansing's reply to Jay, [1919 pre-October 22] (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Robert Lansing: cable to Polk transmitting reply to Jay's request for decision about Fiume (copy as received), 1919 October 22 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Memorandum re: presentation of proposed settlement to the Italian people, 1919 October 25 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - [Frank L. Polk]: memorandum of conversation with Tittoni with covering memorandum to Isaiah Bowman (carbons), 1919 October 25, 27 (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Frank L. Polk: cable to the Secretary of State (originating copy, edited), 1919 October 26 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Guglielmo di Imperiali: memorandum to the British Foreign Office re: revisions required in the proposed terms of settlement (copy), 1919 October 27 (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Frank L. Polk: cable to the Secretary of State transmitting Polk's reply to Jay's cable of Oct 19 (originating copy of Polk's cable, draft of Polk's transmitted reply), 1919 October 27-28 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous cables, 1919 October 27-28, undated (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - Isaiah Bowman: draft memorandum to the Secretary of State re: conversation with Tardieu, 1919 October 28 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - Robert Lansing: cable to Polk (drafts, copy), 1919 October 29 (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - [Italian Delegation]: map showing Italian claims, 1919 Nov 2 (copy of original given to the British Delegation, further annotated by Isaiah Bowman), 1919 November 2, December 1 (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Hugo W. Koehler: letters of transmittal to Polk, 1919 November 7-27 (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - "Department's Reply to Five Propositions" submitted by Ammission, Oct 29, 1919 November 10 (Box 21, Folder 61)
    - William Phillips (acting for the Secretary of State): cable in reply to the Ammission proposals (copy), 1919 November 10 (Box 21, Folder 61)
    - Miscellaneous cables (draft, copies), 1919 November 10-19 (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - [Eyre Crowe et al., for the American, British and French representatives]: memorandum inviting Italy to reconsider its position (carbon of final draft, mimeo), [1919 post-November 12] (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - "Comment on the Italian Statement of the American Position" (carbon), 1919 November 17 (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Memorandum listing changes in the American position proposed by Tittoni, 1919 November 17 (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Critique and revision of "a statement of the position of the American Government; which has just been received by cable from Washington," 1919 Oct 27, 1919 November 19 (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - "Extract from despatch from Lord Curzon to Eyre Crowe" re: circulation of "the Marquis Imperiali's memorandum, together with the American Commentary thereon" (annotated by Isaiah Bowman), 1919 November 26 (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - H. S. Knapp: memorandum to Polk re: the situation in the Adriatic, 1919 November 27 (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Hugo W. Koehler and N. A. McCully: memoranda to Polk transmitting dispatches from Rome, London, and the Adriatic, 1919 November 28 - December 6 (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - [Tommaso Tittoni]: memoranda to Polk representing, or purporting to represent, the American position (annotated by Douglas W. Johnson and a person unnamed), [1919 pre-November 29] (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - [Italian Delegation]: map showing the "Volosca 'Strip'" (copy of original given to the American Delegation, further annotated by Isaiah Bowman), 1919 November 29 (Box 21, Folder 71)
    - [Italian Delegation?]: map showing proposed lines of settlement, 1919 Dec 1 (copy of original given to the British Delegation and "later shown to Clemenceau," further annotated), [post-1919 December 1] (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - N. A. McCully: memorandum to Polk re: "Adriatic Situation - Proposed Telegram to State Department,", 1919 December 5 (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - Cables re: the President's note of 1920 Feb 14 (draft, copies), 1920 February 17-23 (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - Draft cable to Hugh Wallace re: letting Nikola P. Pašić see copies of Wilson's correspondence with Lloyd George and Millerand, 1920 February 20 (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Albert Billings Ruddock: memorandum re: reply to Slavko Y. Grujić's request for copies of Wilson's correspondence with Lloyd George and Millerand, 1920 February 20 (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Chronology--Adriatic Question, 1919 Dec 9 - 1920 Feb 17 (Box 22, Folder 76)
    - "Record of [publication of], Adriatic Memoranda,", 1920 March 2 (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - Department of State, Division of Foreign Intelligence: The Adriatic Question: Papers Relating to the Italian-Jugoslav Boundary, 1920 April 12 (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Douglas W. Johnson: memoranda and annotated maps re: "the so-called American line in Istria,", undated (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - [Douglas W. Johnson]: memorandum re: terms of settlement acceptable to Yugoslavia, undated (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - [André Tardieu]: memorandum re: acceptability of unidentified draft to Allied leaders (pencil), undated (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - Memorandum re: terms of settlement proposed by Italy, undated (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - "Resume of Negotiations in re: Adriatic Problem" (carbon, annotated "Highly Confidential"), undated (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - Maps, undated (Box 22, Folder 84)
  - Aerial Navigation Convention
    - H. S. Knapp: memorandum and related papers re: the report of the Patent Office on Article 18, 1919 August 30 - September 9 (Box 22, Folder 85)
    - Memorandum re: proposed rules (carbon, in French), 1919 September 18 (Box 22, Folder 86)
    - Proof (printed; annotated by James B. Scott), [1919 Sep] (Box 22, Folder 87)
    - James B. Scott: memoranda re: progress of negotiations, [1919 Sep] (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - Convention portant réglementation de lanavigation aérienne (13 octobre 1919.) (Textes francais, anglais, italien), [post-1919 October 13] (Box 22, Folder 89)
  - Albania
    - William Warfield, Director, American Red Cross, Unit to Albania: memorandum re: "The Frontiers of Albania" (carbon), 1919 September 27 (Box 22, Folder 90)
    - "Draft Memorandum as to the Form of the Albanian Mandate," "Memorandum as to the Form of the Albanian Mandate" (carbons), [1919 post-November 12] (Box 22, Folder 91)
    - William Warfield, Commissioner to Albania, American Red Cross: letter to William H. Buckler re: conditions in Albania (copy), 1919 November 17 (Box 22, Folder 92)
    - Archibald Cary Coolidge: memorandum, "The Present Situation in Albania,", [1919] (Box 22, Folder 93)
  - Alien Property Custodian
    - Draft memorandum re: payment of claims (carbon), [1917?] (Box 22, Folder 94)